Guide to the Stanford University Alumni Collection SC1278
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University Alumni Collection
1900-2010
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
SC1278
22.75 Linear Feet (26 boxes)
Scope and Contents
The Stanford Alumni Collection consists of letters, email, texts, student scrapbooks, photographs, websites, audio and video recordings, posters, flyers, records of student organizations, and more. Materials have been donated to the Stanford University Archives for permanent retention, or loaned for selective scanning, and returned to donors.
This collection was created as part of the Stanford Alumni Legacy Project (SALP) initiative. SALP focuses on collecting, preserving, and providing long-term access to student materials created by Stanford alumni during their time on the farm.
Arrangement
Collection materials are described alphabetically in the finding aid by last name of donor. Boxes are listed by accession numbers (ARCH-YYYY-###), which are provided in the finding aid. Alumni class graduation years are indicated as provided.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Separated Materials
Where appropriate, certain materials have been added to other collections. For example, correspondence between students and their families have been added to the Stanford Student Letters and Memoirs Collection (SC0103); football programs and miscellany have been added to the Stanford University, Department of Athletics, Football Collection (SC1185); and miscellaneous pieces of ephemera have been added to the Stanford University Publications and Ephemera Collection (SC4000).
Student life.; Stanford alumni; College students -- California.
- Andrews, Helmus Weddel (Class of 1915), Accession ARCH-2016-027
  - Andrews, Helmus Weddel photograph album, circa 1911-1915 (Box 1)
- Andrews, Rupert Blake (Class of 1914), Accession ARCH-2016-026
  - Andrews, Rupert Blake photograph album, circa 1911-1914 (Box 1)
- Bailey, George (Class of 1957), Accession ARCH-2017-031
  - Digital Scans & Photographs of Prom 1955; El Campo Homecoming (1955/1956), Rose Bowl float (1957); and Reunion Homecoming 2007, 1955-2007
- Bartlett, Mabel (Class of 1909), Accession ARCH-2016-034
  - Scrapbook, circa 1906-1909
- Berry, Velda Hancock (Attended 1919-1923) & Othmar Berarde Berry (Class of 1924), Accession ARCH-2016-029
  - Velda Hancock & Othmar Berarde Berry wedding journal, 1924-03-18
- Black, Dorothy Dale (Class of 1944), Accession ARCH-2016-130
  - Photograph; San Jose State College Record Card; Stanford University Transcript, 1943-1945 (Box 1)
- Brobst Gilbert, Laurel Hutton (Class of 1961, MA 1962), Accession ARCH-2016-020
  - Brobst Gilbert, Laurel Hutton Stanford student diary pages, 1959-1960
    Overseas Studies
- Christiansen, Susan Putnam (Class of 1960, MA 1961), Accession ARCH-2016-023
  - Christiansen, Susan Putnam student material and research files, circa 1957-2010 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Student materials and reserach files about several Stanford topics including the Stanford family, Stanford architecture, and restoration of the Stanford mansion in Sacramento. Included are slides of Sacramento Stanford Mansion restoration and audiocassette recordings of talks given by Christiansen at Stanford Memorial Church in 2003.
    Stanford residences -- Sacramento.; Campus planning -- California -- Stanford; Stanford family.
- Condee, Newcomb (Class of 1919), ARCH-2016-079
  - Condee, Newcomb photograph in front of Encina Hall, 1917
- Doble, Jean (Class of 1965), Accession ARCH-2017-032
  - Indian Stickers (scans)
- De Campos, Camille (Class of 1961), Accession ARCH-2017-137
  - Branner photographs and newsletters, circa 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dance cards, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Registration cards, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Social Standards made by and for the Women Students of Stanford University, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Eating Clubs, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Musical and performance programs, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs and Stanford Daily press pass, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sports programs and ephemera, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stanford ephemera, circa 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Local menus: Trader Vic's, Saint Michael's Alley, Outside at the Inside, circa 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Deitac, Dan (Class of 1974), Accession ARCH-2017-106
  - Student record sheet from time capsule buried underneath the quad, 1974 (Box 1)
- Elliott, Louis Dunshee (Class of 1911), Accession ARCH-2017-330
  - Datebooks, 1900-1906 (Box 1)
- Etienne, Robert (Class of 1936), Accession ARCH-2017-103
  - Photographs and student records (Box 1)
- Ferguson, Nancie Brown (Class of 1954), Accession ARCH-2015-016
  - Ferguson, Nancie Brown scrapbook, 1950
- Fletcher, Charles Gross (Class of 1924), Accession ARCH-2018-089
  - Swimming - photograph of swim team and letter re world record, 1923 (Box 1)
  - Senior Week Dope, 1924 (Box 1)
- Franz, Britta Lion (Class of 1950), Accession ARCH-2016-033
  - Instructions for Elementary Golfers by Sylvia Potter Cain, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stanford University Bulletin, Credential Bulletin, School of Education, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stanford University, School of Education, Annual Announcement, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Traditions cartoons, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Blushing Deep and Paling, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Rose Bowl parade float photographs, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stanford University 'Varsity Squad' program by The White House, San Francisco (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Centennial Gaieties Revue & Performing Arts Festival (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Gould, Richard Bartlett (Class of 1933), Accession ARCH-2016-034
  - Stanford photograph album, 1930-1935
- Grace, Larry W. (Class of 1960), Accession ARCH-2016-018
  - Scrapbook, 1956-1960
  - Cedro III - 50th mini-reunion slideshow photographs, 2010
- Hall, Benjamin Frederick (Attended 1897), Accession ARCH-2016-036
  - Leland Stanford Junior University registration cards, 1897-1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Palo Alto/Stanford brochure, pre 1906 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellany, circa 1897-1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Handy, Jr., Ralph P. (Class of 1951), Accession ARCH-2017-079
  - New student orientation material, including transfer student orientation, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Information on Stanford Village (Box 1)
  - Your Campus Wardrobe...According to Collier's (Box 1)
  - Library orientation material, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Pine Hill Real Estate (Box 2)
  - Dance and game tickets (Box 2)
  - Slides, 1949-1951 (Box 2)
- Hittman, Suzanne (Class of 1952), Accession ARCH-2017-318
  - Hoover Library brochure, circa 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Laguinita and Branner material, circa 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Handbooks and directories, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Class Week program, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Musical programs, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Hockensmith, Sharon Fogleman (Class of 1965), Accession ARCH-2015-155
  - Freshman scrapbook (1961-1962); Sophomore scrapbook (1962-1963), 1961-1963 (Box 1)
- Jurney, Peter (Class of 1962, AM 1964), Accession ARCH-207-039
  - Italy Group I photographs (scans), 1960-1961
- Kattan, Francisco (MS 1987, MS 1989), Accession ARCH-2017-037
  - Photograph of Stanford Amateur Radio Club, circa 1986
    “Stanford Amateur Radio Club circa 1986. At the time the club had its "Radio Shack" trailer on Searsville Road. This is a picture of myself in the trailer at the radio shack. As an international student (from Honduras), phone calls home were very expensive at the time. This is how I and many other international students communicated with with our families at the time.”
- Kennedy, Robin Hamill (Class of 1968), Accession ARCH-2016-014
  - Scrapbook "Robin at Stanford - Volume 1", 1964-1967
  - Scrapbook "Robin at Stanford - Volume 2", 1967-1968
- Kirschenbaum, Ellis (Class of 1969), Accession ARCH-2017-038
  - April 3rd Movement materials, 1969
- Lange, Susan Tarr (Class of 1966), Accession ARCH-2017-062
  - Photographs
    2 photographs from Italy VII, and one from Roble Hall 3-B.
  - Memoirs (various) (Box 1)
    Topics include: Stanford-Notre Dame game, meeting husband, Escondido Village, 50th Reunion.
- Leybold, Dennis (Class of 1976), Accession ARCH-2018-119
  - Stanford Fire Program photograph, circa 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fencing Photographs, circa 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fenching Material, circa 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Maxwell, Nancy Randolph (Class of 1956), Accession ARCH-2016-015
  - Freshman scrapbook, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
- McNitt, Elizabeth Church (Class of 1936), Accession ARCH-2016-022
  - Elizabeth Church McNitt, President of National Association of University Dames, letter to the wives of Stanford students, 1939-09-25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Panhellenic bidding contract, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten invitation to Mr. and Mrs. Hoover, inviting them to Lagunita Court, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Handwritten invitation to Mr. Jackson, inviting him to Lagunita Court, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Note requesting Elizabeth Church McNitt act as hostess to Mrs. Hoover after dinner at coffee, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Christmas musical service in Memorial Church, 1934-12-16 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Description of university residences for women (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Daily article clipping re compensation for sponsors in Encina, but not Roble, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- O'Neill, Marshall (Associate Director W.W. Hansen Laboratories, 1952-1990), Acccession ARCH-2017-034
  - Field Passes (scans), 1948
- Porter, Anne Norton (Class of 1959, AM 1960), Accession ARCH-2017-035
  - Scrapbook (scans), 1957-2005
- Price, Donald (Class of 1953), Accession ARCH-2017-046
  - Memoir re Stanford Band (Box 1)
- St Geme, Monica (Class of 1954), Accession ARCH-2017-036
  - Photographs (scans), 1952-1984
- Stebbins family, Accession ARCH-2017-138
  Family members include Reverend Horation Stebbins (Member of original Board of Trustees); Horation Ward Stebbins (professor of Mechanical Engineering); Amelia Stebbins (Class of 1934); and J. Ward Keesling (Class of 1962).
  - "Merry Christmas" book with verses by Elsie T. Stebbins, 1919 (Box 1)
  - "Beligum" by David Starr Jordan, 1915 Oct 9 (Box 1)
  - Letters from Ray Lyman Wilbur re endowment, 1922-1927 (Box 1)
- Tanner, Carol Scilacci & Douglas Tanner (Class of 1975), Accession ARCH-2016-016
  - Tanner, Carol Scilacci & Douglas Tanner photograph album, 1972-1974
- Trainor, Shelly Williams (Class of 1977), Accession ARCH-2017-130
  - Student Materials, 1973-1977 (Box 1)
    Admissions materials, clippings, Women's Rugby, Senior Class officer election posters, Manzanita musical show "Applause" program, Hammer & Coffin material.